

Nicolás Martínez

Full Stack Engineer

Montevideo, Uruguay

(+598) 098 183 793

□ nicomb3@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/nicolas-martinez-baston/

github.com/nmartinezb3

Profile

Hi, I'm Nicolás Martínez, a 28 years-old Computer Engineer who graduated from Facultad de Ingenieria of Universidad de la Republica, Uruguay. I am passionate about web and mobile development, especially using React.js, Node.js, and Python-Django, although I am always learning new technologies that new challenges demands.

Technical Skills

- React (advanced)
- Node.js (advanced)
- MongoDB (advanced)
- PostgreSQL (advanced)

- Python/Django (upper-intermediate)
- JavaScript (advanced)
- React Native (advanced)
- HTML/CSS (advanced)

Work Experience

Full Stack Engineer

March 2018 - Present

Nobly Point of Sale

Nobly is a UK-based company that provides a whole suite of products around its point of sale, inventory management, and CRM platform. Based on an iPad-based POS and a back office web application, it offers +20 complex sales and finance reports, inventory tracking, payment integrations, among others, offering a complete solution for coffee shops, restaurants, and retail stores all over the world.

In Nobly I work as a Full Stack Engineer in charge of the design and development of the Nobly suite of products:

- o Nobly Core Server, built with a Node.js microservices architecture and MongoDB
- Nobly Back Office web app for store management, dashboard, reports, inventory tracking, third-party apps integration. Built with React and Node.
- o Nobly GO, mobile app that provides access to the main Nobly reports. Built with React Native (Android and iOS).
- Nobly Delivery, a complete delivery solution for restaurants and shops built with React Native (Android and iOS), Node and Mongo DB
- Nobly KDS (Kitchen Display System) tablet app built with React Native to display real-time orders on the restaurant's kitchens

Full Stack Developer

February 2016 - March 2018

Octobot - www.octobot.io

Octobot is an Uruguayan-based software factory specialized in web and mobile development.

During my journey in Octobot I have been involved in several projects for many US-based startups and companies, developing web applications with Python-Django, Node.js, React, Postgres SQL and Mongo DB.

SysAdmin & Software Developer

July 2013 - February 2016

SAICO Sistemas - www.saico.com.uy

SAICO Sistemas is a software development company specialized in business administration software, such as accounting, human resources, sales, among others.

During my 3 years on SAICO, I worked as a Java developer as well as a SysAdmin in charge of the administration of networks and infrastructure of Linux and Windows servers.

Personal Projects

Prono 2019 - Present

Prono is a work-in-progress mobile application that offers surf forecasts for different beaches along the Uruguayan coast. By consuming public APIs and web scraping, it recovers data from well-known surf forecast providers, offering an easy to use interface with detailed information, tips, and swell forecasts for different surfing spots.

Prono is built with React Native, Node.js, and Mongo DB.

Education

Computer Engineer 2010 - 2018

Facultad de Ingeniería, Universidad de la República